Ashwin Shrestha

Phone: 9843729356 | Email: shrashwiniw@gmail.com

Linked In Profile: https://np.linkedin.com/in/ashwin-shrestha-7545a2101

Website: Web profile

Address: Chamati, Kathmandu, Bagmati, Nepal

OBJECTIVE

My career has revolved around as an ios developer for two and half years at ebPearls Pvt. Ltd and then currently six months at Insight Workshop. In the past three years, I have developed strong team work skills and interpersonal expertise that has helped me add value to my employer. I make it my goal to create mobile applications with the user in mind, and with a useable and intuitive user interface experience. I also understand the importance of creating highly readable and easily maintainable source code. I am constantly striving to learn new technologies and look to ways to better myself in this rapidly changing industry.

EDUCATION

Kathmandu University 2011-2015

Bachelor of Computer Engineering.

Orchid Public Higher Secondary School 2009-2011

HSEB in Science Faculty

Siddhartha Shishu Sadan 1998-2009

SLC

EXPERIENCE

Senior iOS Developer at Insight Workshop

- December 2017 Present
 - + Started working as senior ios developer at Insight Workshop with responsibility to start new department of mobile apps in the office along with android app development.
 - + Working on Projects:
 - 1. **Crunch (los App)**: A go-to dishes and resturant search ios app in local area through swipe like/ dislike to get recommendation of dish to eat or resturant to eat at. (Under development)
 - **2. Biometric Dashboard (los App):** A health care app, to sync blood pressure measurement readings from bluetooth enabled health care device to mobile app. (Under development)

Associate Team Lead (los Development) at ebPearls Technology Pvt. Ltd.

- January 2017 November 2017
 - + After working as los developer for more than an year, I was offered a promotion of Associate Team Lead (los Development).
 - + Achievement: Worked with the team, help manage the team and guide developers on some wonderful project like:
 - 1. **Crewgo:** A hire and manage staff app, where user can manage bookings & staff through an efficient self-service solution. Available in app store: Crewgo

los Developer at ebPearls Technology Pvt. Ltd.

September 2015 – December 2016

- + Due to my quick learning abilities and zeal in Object Oriented Programming during my Internship Project, I was offered job of full time Ios developer at ebpearls.
- + Achievement: Worked on some of the wonderful ios apps and successfully deployed it in app store.
 - 1. **The City of Albany App:** The Albany App provides information to residents about Bins & Waste, Events, Available in app store: The City of Albany App
 - 2. **Live Bid:** A real time live bidding platform where users can make offers and bid on different properties at auctions on the real estate market Available in app store: LiveBid
 - 3. **Quint:** Create own invitations when selecting from over 100+ contemporary designs with photographic backgrounds. Available in app store: Quint

Intern at ebPearls Technology Pvt. Ltd.

June 2015 - August 2015

+ Learn working in the industry and industry level products with sample products.

FREELANCED-PROJECTS

- 1. **Dreesti- Your In hand astrologer!**: With Dreesti Your in hand Astrologer, you get access over your life. You can learn why things have been the way it is so far. You shall also be able to learn what could happen in the future. Moreover, you can comfort yourself and get over the turmoil in your life. Available in app store at: **Dreesti**
- **2. TUV Project Updates**: "TUV Project Updates" is an enterprise app for TÜV SÜD America, which helps track the projects in the system, their milestone levels and give employees notifications about the current project status on new updates.
- **3. Octagon**: Octagon app is for TÜV SÜD America is used to update customers on the status of their projects. Updates will be sent on various milestones to be reached to complete the project. Available in app store at: Octagon
- **4. Haku TV**: HakuTV allows you to watch iptv streams from its server on your iphone. Available in app store at: Haku TV
- **5. Sastodeal :** Sastodeal is one of Nepal's leading E-Commerce portal. We are a one stop online store for genuine apparel, electronics, home & living and much much more. Use our Sastodeal App for quick and easy shopping solutions. Shop on Nepal's leading E-Commerce store for a generous selection of products ranging from fashion, electronics, fitness and more. Be a part of the Sastodeal's shopping culture by purchasing superior quality revolutionary products. Available in ios Store: Sastodeal

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Swift, Objective-C, C, Java
- Web Skills: HTML, CSS
- Scripting Language: JavaScript, PHP
- Database: MySQL
- Tools: Xcode, Android Studio, Apache, Eclipse, Netbeans, XAMPP
- **Technical:** Linux, Object Oriented Programming, Database System, Algorithm, Web Development.
- Soft Skill: Interpersonal expertise, Team work, Project Analysis & Estimation

ACHIEVEMENT AND ACTIVITIES

- **Re-Nepal Hackathon 2015:** 1st runner up in Hackathon organized by Kathmandu Engineering College, Kathmandu, Nepal.
- LTSP -Help Nepal: Volunteered for LTSP system deployment at Salyan, Nepal. (Year 2015)
- LTSP -Help Nepal: Volunteered for LTSP system monitoring at Saptari, Gaighat and Sunsari, Nepal. (Year 2014)
- **K.U. I.T. Meet 2014:** Human Recourse Management for the Information Technology meet up at Kathmandu University.
- K.U. I.T. Meet 2013: Volunteered for the Information Technology meet up at Kathmandu University.

REFRENCES

Available upon request